Hello English learners, welcome
back to English POD, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine so Marco,
you've been shopping a lot lately.
I have and this dialogue
or this lesson today
is one of my favorite
pieces of furniture
or maybe appliances that I've
bought recently and it's a TV.
Alright, so I'd even go for
electronics with that one, the
electronics department is
somewhere you like to hang out.
Well, I mean I think
every guy loves, you
know, like a big screen
TV and a home theater
system so you just like
go deaf after watching.
Why is that?
Is bigger really better when
it comes to like a 70 inch TV?
Well, I don't know, I
think, yeah, the whole
experience of just
seeing this movie on this
huge TV and like having all the sound and I
don't know, it's just something about that.
Or watching a football game with
your buddies and you can actually watch.
Okay, that I can appreciate but
we've got a couple of great words
for you, we're going to preview
in today's vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
Okay, so on vocabulary preview today,
we're going to be looking at two words.
The first one is to appreciate.
Alright, so this basically means to like.
Yeah, you appreciate
someone but in this
context to enjoy or take
advantage of something.
So maybe you hear this
with a couple of two people
who are fighting and
the girl says to the guy.
You don't appreciate
me so he doesn't really
care about her in the
way that she wants
him to or you could
say this about a TV, for
example, I can't
appreciate my PS3, my great
awesome console, my
gaming system because my
TV's not good enough or
big enough or big enough.
Or big enough.
So this means that it could be a
lot better if I just bought a better TV.
Right, and if you buy a better TV, then
you basically are upgrading or to upgrade.
Okay, so this verb to
upgrade means to go
from something that's okay
to something that's better.
Exactly.
So in previous lessons, we've seen to get
a complimentary upgrade, for example, on
a flight or in a hotel.
I like that.
Well, you can also get
an upgrade on a computer,
you say, well, my computer's from
1994, I really need to get an upgrade.
Yeah, for sure.
So to upgrade.
Now we're going to be listening to this
dialogue for the first time, we're going to
be buying a TV, so let's listen.
Seriously, I don't know why
we need to get a new TV.
Honey, I told you already.
I can't appreciate the
graphics level and detail
of the games on my
PlayStation 3 on our old TV.
Good afternoon, folks.
How can I be of service today?
I'm looking to upgrade to a
newer, bigger television set.
You've come to the right place.
What size are you looking for?
Just a normal size TV for a living room.
I see.
Well, this set here is on sale.
It's a 46 inch HTTV screen
and it has all the works.
Three HDMI connectors,
USB, VGA and S-video ports.
It even has a DVI port so you
can hook up your PC or laptop.
This is without a doubt, the
company home theater experience.
This is exactly what I need.
Can you imagine watching movies
or playing video games on this thing?
Honey, I think it's a bit too big.
I don't even think it
will fit in our living room.
Not to worry, we will deliver
and install it in your home.
It comes with a wall mount so you can
just hang it on the wall like a picture.
This is great.
How much will this set in that?
Lucky for you, this is the last one
we have in stock, so it's half off.
I'll take it.
All right, so I'm going
to have to defer to
you, Marco, on some
of these words in today's
language takeaway because
they're all about TV specifics.
Language takeaway.
All right, the first word
that we're going to
be looking at is graphics,
the graphics level.
All right, so you might
have heard this before
with the phrase graphic design or someone
who designs images, but in this case we're
talking about graphics, so the
way things appear on your TV.
So basically the pictures, right?
So he wanted to
appreciate the graphics of his
PlayStation 3 better, and
that's why he wanted a new TV.
All right, we could say my
computer has amazing graphics.
It means games are
really fun because they
look good, or this game
has amazing graphics.
So the game has, you know, places
or scenery that looks really, really real.
All right, so graphics,
but some kinds of TVs
are made to provide those wonderful
graphics, and those are called HDTV.
Right, an HDTV, or that's an
acronym for High Definition Television.
All right, and I heard
some actors and actresses
were complaining
about HDTV because this
the picture quality is
so good that you can
see all of the little
problems on their face,
the little wrinkles and the
pimples and the scars, so be careful,
because one day we're going
to be able to see way too much.
Exactly, so on high
definition television, that's
basically what you get is better
definition, better level of graphics.
So more pixels per inch,
you can see a lot more clarity.
Right, so an HDTV.
The next thing we're
talking about is actually
kind of related to the back part of
your TV where you plug things in.
Sometimes it's on the
side, sometimes on the back.
Well, there are different
names for different
kinds of plugs, so today we're
going to talk about two of those.
One of them is USB.
Right, this TV has a USB port, which
basically stands for Universal Serial Bus.
All right, so port is a place
where you plug something in.
Your computer has a lot of ports as well,
but USB is maybe more common for people who
have iPods or computers,
because this is how
we normally connect
things to our computers.
So, in this case, this
television, you could
connect maybe your iPod and
reproduce videos or pictures onto the TV.
Awesome, or in the second case, we have
a DVI port, so DVI, you're going to have to
tell me about this one,
Marco, because I'm not so sure.
Well, a DVI is basically
a digital video input,
so basically you can connect your computer
to the TV and see what's on your screen.
Nice, and so if you
have a bunch of movies
stored on your computer, you can
just plug it into the TV and watch.
Or you can even navigate
the internet on a big screen TV.
That's cool.
Yeah.
All right, so what are these
three HDMI connectors?
All right, well, this is a new technology,
basically, you know, how before you used
to get your DVI player,
your VHS, and you had
three cables, two for
sound and one for video.
Yeah, the red yellow and white cables.
Exactly.
So this new type of
cable or technology,
with one cable, it
takes all the information
to the TV, so just one
cable for everything.
Oh, nice, because my
problem is I always used
to put the wrong
cable in the wrong port,
so I'd have the red cable in the yellow
port, and then I'd say, "Where's the video?
I can't see.
All I can do is listen.
" Yeah, it happens.
So with this, now
it's easy, and well, it
even, it's a little bit
more organized, because
I remember I used to
have a TV and have, and
I had a lot of different
things connected to it.
It was just this big spider web
in the back with all these cables.
So an HDMI high-definition multimedia
interface connector, and what else do we have?
The last thing we're
talking about is actually
the place to put your
TV, so a lot of people
now are putting
their TVs on walls, like
paintings, because these TVs are
so thin, so we call this a wall mount.
So a mount to mount
something is also a verb, right?
Yeah, it means to put
something up or to hang
something up, so many people like
to mount their trophies, to show off.
Very good.
So this is what we're doing with the TV.
We're going to mount it
on the wall, like a painting.
Cool.
So those are our words
for language takeaway.
Let's take another
listen to today's dialogue.
We're going to slow it down this time,
and really figure out what's going on.
Seriously, I don't know why
we need to get a new TV.
Honey, I told you already.
I can appreciate the
graphics level and
detail of the games on my
PlayStation 3 on our old TV.
Good afternoon, folks.
How can I be of service today?
I'm looking to upgrade to a
newer, bigger television set.
You've come to the right place.
What size are you looking for?
Just a normal size TV for a living room.
I see.
Well, this set here is on sale.
A 46 inch HTTV screen
and it has all the works.
Three HDMI connectors,
USB, VGA and S-video ports.
It even has a DVI port so you
can hook up your PC or laptop.
This is without a doubt.
The complete home theater experience.
This is exactly what I need.
Can you imagine watching movies
or playing video games on this thing?
Honey, I think it's a bit too big.
I don't even think it
will fit in our living room.
Not to worry, we will deliver
and install it in your home.
It comes with a wall mount so you can
just hang it on the wall like a picture.
This is great.
How much will this set me back?
Lucky for you, this is the
last one we have in stock.
So it's half off.
I'll take it.
All right, so now we're
going to be taking a
look at three different phrases that we
saw in this dialogue in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right.
This first phrase is
definitely one that I use a lot.
We can talk about
food, we can talk about
electronics, we can
talk about most different
things, but the phrase
here is the works.
He's getting the works.
All right.
That means any option he could
get, any possibility he wants it all.
All right.
So if you're getting a
new car, for example,
right, you're getting the
high definition sound system.
You're getting nice tires, leather seats.
You're getting the works.
All right.
Or if you're getting
a hamburger and you
want the works, you're
getting it with cheese
and lettuce and tomato and
pepper and bacon and, you
know, it means every
option you're getting it all.
The works.
So I think this word
is so versatile that we
should maybe listen
to some more examples.
Example one.
The bridegroom was wearing a
morning suit, top hat, gloves, the works.
Example two.
He spent over $10,000 on
his home theater system.
He got all the works.
Example three.
I bought a new car
with all the works,
magnesium rims, custom
paint and leather seats.
So now that we've seen the works on the
home theater system, he needs to hook it up.
All right.
So this is an important part and a
very exciting part of a new purchase.
So when you buy something,
you have to hook it up.
That means you have
to plug things together.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So we plug things into
the wall for electricity,
but also hook up, maybe those, those cores
you were talking about earlier, that HDMI
connector that's called
hooking up or connecting.
So you would hook up your
DVD player to your television.
All right.
I could ask you, did you hook up those
new speakers to your big TV yesterday?
Very good.
Right.
So to connect, it's another
way of saying to connect.
And finally, the big
event when you're buying
something is the end when
you have to actually pay.
And this guy's a little bit worried that
the things he wants cost a lot of money.
So he asks a really great question.
Yeah, he said, "How
much will this set me back?
" Okay.
This sounds a little
weird at first because
you could just say,
"How much will this cost?
" But he's speaking in a
very colloquial way, very
familiar and he says, "How
much will this set me back?
" Right.
So how much will this cost me?
Mm-hmm.
So how much am I actually going to spend?
So it's just a different way of
saying how much does it cost.
But it's, like you say, more
colloquial, it's a lot more native-like.
Exactly.
When you're paper,
you don't want to write
this, this will set you
back $500 in economics,
but we'd say this in spoken language
and our normal daily lives with friends.
Mm-hmm.
So why don't we listen to a couple
more examples of set me back?
Example one.
This unexpected expense is going to
set us back a couple thousand dollars.
Example two.
My fancy dinner at the restaurant
last night really set us back.
Example three.
I feel guilty about buying this coat.
It sent me back over $300.
All right, great.
So now that we've taken
a look at those great
phrases and with some
good examples, why don't
we listen to this dialogue one last time?
Seriously, I don't know why
we need to get a new TV.
Honey, I told you already.
I can't appreciate the
graphics level and detail
the games on my
PlayStation 3 on our old TV.
Good afternoon, folks.
How can I be of service today?
I'm looking to upgrade to a
newer, bigger television set.
You've come to the right place.
What size are you looking for?
Just a normal sized TV for a living room.
I see.
Well, this set here is on sale.
It's a 46 inch HTTV screen
and it has all the works.
Three HDMI connectors,
USB, VGA and S-video ports.
It even has a DVI port so you
can hook up your PC or laptop.
This is without a doubt,
decumbly home theater experience.
This is exactly what I need.
Can you imagine watching movies
or playing video games on this thing?
Honey, I think it's a bit too big.
I don't even think it
will fit in our living room.
Not to worry, we will deliver
and install it in your home.
It comes with a wall mount so you can
just hang it on the wall like a picture.
This is great.
How much will this set me back?
Lucky for you, this is the
last one we have in stock.
So it's half off, I'll take it.
Okay, so a big TV, I
think, I don't know, I
think it's just a great
thing to have at home.
Not to, you know,
spend too much time in
front of the TV, but it's good
to sit down and watch a movie.
It's nice because, you know, now there's so
many different things you can do with it.
You can hook up your
computer, you can buy
projector, you can play
your PS3 or your Wii.
So I think there's a
lot to do and it's just
wonderful how great graphics have
come in just like the last five years.
What do you think about having a television
set, for example, in the bathroom?
I would say it's a really
bad idea, but I think
if I have a bathtub, I
think it'd be really cool.
Because, you know, some people don't like
having a television set in their bedroom.
I agree with this.
I agree.
Because I think it's
really important that you
have peace and quiet
in your bedroom because
it's kind of like, for
me, it's an important
space where I can
just relax and be quiet
and I like reading a
lot, so if I have a TV,
maybe I'll watch more TV, but I
much rather read a book before bed.
True.
Yeah, I definitely agree.
But, you know, I've seen
people that have TVs
in their living rooms, in their dining
rooms, in their kitchen, so they're watching
something while they're
cooking and even in the bathroom.
Like you say, in a
bathtub, well, it's nice,
but some of them I've seen in
front of the toilet or something.
I would say that the one in the kitchen is
nice because if you spend a lot of time in
the kitchen, you can
watch the news while
you're cooking or you can actually
watch cooking shows and try and practice.
Or soap operas.
Ooh.
So I guess it depends
on the person, it depends
on how much you
watch TV, but I'm curious
to know what our listeners have to say
about TVs and big electronics purchases.
Alright, so come to our
website englishpot.com.
If you have any
questions or any doubts
regarding the lesson or any
suggestions, you can let us know.
Otherwise, we'll be there to
just talk and practice that English.
And of course, send us
your suggestions for future
lessons we love to know what
you're interested in learning about.
Alright, we'll see you guys there.
Alright.
Bye, everyone.